<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Lance Wonderland</title>
    <link>http://lancechuang.github.io/lance_blog/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Lance Wonderland</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lancechuang.github.io/lance_blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Sum - Unique Pair</title>
      <link>http://lancechuang.github.io/lance_blog/post/2018-09-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lancechuang.github.io/lance_blog/post/2018-09-11/</guid>
      <description>Description Given an array of integers, find how many unique pairs in the array such that their sum is equal to a specific target number. Please return the number of pairs. Example Given nums = [1,1,2,45,46,46], target = 47 return 2 1 + 46 = 47 2 + 45 = 47  想法：要找到所有的不同組合，所以不能用一般hash的方式
這邊使用 2 pointer解
 sort arry, 小的部分會在左邊，大的會在右邊 設定while條件為left &amp;lt; right，當兩個pointer指的數相加大於target，將右指針向內縮; 若小於target，則往右移動左指針 當pointer數加起來等於target，count ++, 左右指針向內縮，因為array有可能會有重複數字且題目是要unique pair，所以要做去重的動作： 若left指向的數和上個一樣，則再往右跑; 若right指向數和上個一樣，則向左跑  https://repl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unix Command Line</title>
      <link>http://lancechuang.github.io/lance_blog/post/2018-08-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lancechuang.github.io/lance_blog/post/2018-08-29/</guid>
      <description>ls   stands for &amp;ldquo;list&amp;rdquo; lists the contents of a directory
  ls -l   long listing format gives additional info of files, size, date of last exist&amp;hellip;.
  ls -lh   long listing format + print human readable format
  ls -lSh   sorted by the size and then by the date of exist time
  ls [another directory]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>394. Decode String - Google Amazon Bloomberg Oracle</title>
      <link>http://lancechuang.github.io/lance_blog/post/2018-08-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lancechuang.github.io/lance_blog/post/2018-08-26/</guid>
      <description>題目來自Leetcode
題目  The encoding rule is: k[encoded_string], where the encoded_string inside the square brackets is being repeated exactly k times. Note that k is guaranteed to be a positive integer. You may assume that the input string is always valid; No extra white spaces, square brackets are well-formed, etc. Furthermore, you may assume that the original data does not contain any digits and that digits are only for those repeat numbers, k.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic: the website designer for Hugo</title>
      <link>http://lancechuang.github.io/lance_blog/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lancechuang.github.io/lance_blog/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Academic is a framework to help you create a beautiful website quickly. Perfect for personal sites, blogs, or business/project sites. Check out the latest demo of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes. Then head on over to the Quick Start guide or take a look at the Release Notes.

Key features:
 Easily manage various content including homepage, blog posts, publications, talks, and projects Extensible via color themes and widgets/plugins Write in Markdown for easy formatting and code highlighting, with LaTeX for mathematical expressions Social/academic network linking, Google Analytics, and Disqus comments Responsive and mobile friendly Simple and refreshing one page design Multilingual and easy to customize  Color Themes Academic is available in different color themes and font themes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>